Narrator: There are two types of twins: non-identical twins, who don’t look the same,
and identical twins, who look exactly the same.
But did you know that there are also ‘twin strangers’ – people who look the same,
but are not related at all?
They say we all have seven twin strangers in the world – seven people who are not our relatives,
but who look nearly identical to us.
On the twentieth of March twenty fifteen, three friends from Dublin began a unique challenge.
Niamh: Hi, I’m Niamh.
Terence: I’m Terence.
Harry: And I’m Harry.
Niamh: And we’re trying to find our twin strangers from anywhere in the world.
Harry: Basically, we’ve set ourselves a challenge and we have one month,
starting from today, erm, to find people that look really, really like us
or almost completely identical.
Narrator: The three friends advertised their project on social media.
Soon messages and photos started coming in from everywhere in the world, especially for Niamh.
After two weeks, Niamh got to meet Karen,
the first of her potential twin strangers.
It was a very exciting meeting.
Niamh and Karen decided to put on the same make-up and do their hair the same way for a photo.
Niamh: So guys, this is it – make-up and hair, what do you think?
Narrator: Niamh continued to search for her other six Twin Strangers,
and she found number two...in Italy!
Niamh: There’s this lovely girl named Luisa that got in touch on the site so
I had this crazy idea – why not go fly and meet her?
Narrator: So Niamh travelled to Genoa on the Italian Riviera.
Niamh: It’s so great to meet you and meet your face!
Narrator: So, what about the boys?
Harry found two or three people like him,
but they weren’t as good as Niamh’s ‘twin strangers’.
Terence received some photos, mainly from the USA, but they weren’t very like him.
He says, ‘I think there are definitely Black guys out there who look like me.’
Soon their online project became a website,
and since then many people have found their ‘twin’ on twinstrangers.com.
Sara, from Sweden, found Shannon, from Ireland, after they both went on the site,
and they met in Dublin.
So, if you’d like to meet your twin stranger,
all you need to do is go to their website, upload a photo, and… who knows?
In a few days’ time, you might find someone who looks just like you!